

# **Ahmed Chiboub**

**Information Security Engineer** 

- **1** Jun 4, 1987
- L'aouina 2045, Tunis, Tunisia
- +216 52 900 666
- Chiboub.13
- in linkedin.com/in/ahmedchiboub
- git github.com/Cybafrost
- Ahmed.chiboub@pm.me

# Skills -

- Information Security Standards
- Network Penetration testing
- WebApp Penetration testing
- Wireless Penetration testing
- Source Code Security auditing
- A Linux Administration
- Windows Administration
- Python
- Java
- Ruby

# Languages

- Arabic
- **English**
- French

#### **About me:**

Information security engineer with intensive experience running simulate a full-scale, high-value penetration test and creating written reports, detailing assessment findings and recommendations.

Well-versed in information security and penetration testing standards with strong critical thinking and able to thrive in fast-paced and challenging environments where accuracy and efficiency matter.

# **Working Experience:**

Since 2016 Head of Technical Department DISA: Counter-Terrorism Division

• Performed penetration tests on the Defense Intelligence and Security Agency networks and systems regularly to emulate threats and improve computer network defense posture.

• Conducted onsite penetration tests from an insider threat perspective.

• Administrated web application periodic security assessment on the D.O.D website and internal Web applications.

• Developed Android and windows rootkits, documents Trojans, shell codes, cell trackers, a Waterholing system and co-performed social engineering operations including Phishing, Smishing and whaling.

2017–2018 **Cyber Security consultant** French Defense: CyberDefense Operation Center

Mission details are Classified.

2014–2016 Information System Administrator DOD: DE

• Integrated security appliances and configured security software such as firewall (Pfsense), intrusion detection system (snort) and Security software (Kaspersky Security Center).

• Planed and implemented systems backups, coordinating recoveries

• Developed utility programs and shell scripts (e.g., backup, integrity checks).

2013–2014 Network Administrator

DOD: DSCI

• Assigned routing protocols (Cisco routers and switches) and configured of authentication and authorization to services.

• Monitored networks to ensure security, availability and Information integrity using tools such as Wireshark, Iptraf, Tcpdump and Nagios.

• Installed security updates and patches.

2013–2014 Information security and end user awareness instructor DOD: CIC

● Taught information Security, cryptography, Networking and basics programming languages (python, bash, Java).

• Organized and conducted Information Security awareness training.

Taught signal intelligence.

## **Education:**

#### Postgraduate Training

03-2019	Certifed Ethical Hacker	EC-Council
10-2018	Opensource Intelligence Training	Nato School Oberammergau
06-2018	Penetration Testing Training	BIT

### Study

,		
2009-2012	Information Technology Military Academy	
	Master of Engineering	
2006-2009	MPCI: Mathematics, Physics, Chemistry and Informatics. Prepara-	

tory School for engineering

Bachelor of science

2006–2002 **Mathematics ⋒** Baccalaureate

9 Avril 1938 high School